Contact

cody.zuschlag@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/cody-zuschlag (LinkedIn)

codyzu.github.io (Personal) github.com/codyzu (Other) medium.com/@codyzus (Blog)

Top Skills

Software Development Node.js Google Cloud Platform

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) French (Full Professional)

Certifications

Microsoft Windows CE Embedded Training

React Summit 2022

Cody Zuschlag

Staff Developer Relations Engineer at NearForm promoting opens source tech and design systems #

Annecy, Auvergne-Rhône-Alpes, France

Summary

Cloud Architect with a passion for Developer Relations. I love cloud first architecture, creating the best developer experience, and sharing technical knowledge to enable developers to create innovative solutions. A backend guru and university instructor with extensive experience with node.js, serverless architecture, managed databases, and developer relations. I'm also interested in breaking down the barriers between designers and developers #

I've attended the following conferences:
Firebase Summit 2019, Madrid, Spain
nodeconf.eu 2017 and 2018, Kilkenny, Ireland
dotJS 2015 and 2016, Paris, France
Mix-IT 2016, Lyon, France
I have also presented trainings on hapijs.

Experience

NearForm

4 years 1 month

Staff Developer Relations Engineer October 2022 - Present (1 year 3 months)

France

Influencing the tech industry by interacting directly with developers. It takes one to know one.

Developer Relations Engineer January 2022 - October 2022 (10 months) France

Helping train NearForm enterprise clients, NearForm engineering staff, and the ecosystem through the development and presentation of rich technical examples, documentation, workshops, and conference talks.

Representing NearForm within the JavaScript community and ecosystem. Collaborating across organization teams.

Following new and emerging technologies and presenting on those both internally and externally.

Preparing the content for presentations, blog posts, recording videos, podcasts, and other content in collaboration with the marketing team. Maintenance of the NearForm tooling and open-source projects.

Senior Software Engineer December 2019 - January 2022 (2 years 2 months) France

Helped architect, build, and promote a design system of systems that allows for tight collaboration for designers and developers across teams, delivery channels, and platforms

Helped build a next-generation serverless CMS framework with a hybrid jamstack combining the advantages of a static site and content as a service framework

Created a Developer Relations strategy and led the developer experience. Worked extensively with Gatsby, Hasura graphql, AWS, React, serverless architecture, and Circle CI.

Cody Factory
Cloud Architect and Developer Relations Consulting
November 2019 - Present (4 years 2 months)
Remote

Tétras - Formation en alternance University Instructor January 2019 - Present (5 years) Annecy-le-Vieux, France

Instructor for university Web Development course teaching JavaScript, node.js, and React for cloud first applications deployed to Google Cloud Platform / Firebase. Tetras is a partnership between the Chambre Syndicale de la Métallurgie de la Haute-Savoie and l'Université Savoie Mont Blanc. I created the above course to prepare 3rd year students with practical cloud first development skills for industry.

Hubware Lead Developer March 2017 - November 2019 (2 years 9 months) France

Leading product architecture including researching solutions and planning and implementing new features.

Leading development team with responsibilities including backlog grooming, story writing, iteration planning (scrum master), code-reviews and enforcing best practices.

Developing node.js back-end service delivered in a docker images, deployed to Google Kubernetes Engine.

Building services deployed on Google Cloud Platform and Firebase including serverless Cloud Functions, Kubernetes, PubSub, and Cloud Firestore NoSQL Database (shared between frontend and backend).

Developed continuous delivery pipeline, including multi-tier test strategy and test coverage statistics.

Authoring technical articles on medium.com and evangelizing services.

Working 100% remote, using Slack + Google Hangouts (with video) for team communication.

Appcelerator Senior Software Engineer January 2017 - February 2017 (2 months)

Helped develop the next generation Arrow MBaaS framework.

REST API builder and API manager built on Node.js and Docker stack.

Axway Senior Software Engineer June 2013 - February 2017 (3 years 9 months) Annecy-le-Vieux, Rhône-Alpes, France

Developed node.js back-end micro-services delivered in docker images for cloud deployment (using Kanban methodology).

Implemented instant deployment into build pipeline to allow instant deployments of entire solution using docker, docker-compose, and docker-machine.

Presented and facilitated workshops to train employees to use new node.js technologies (including migrating services from express to hapi).

Developed and tested user stories for a large scale OSGi and MongoDB based web application written in Java, JavaScript (backbone and jQuery), HTML5, and CSS (less) (using Agile Scrum methodology).

Architected a performance testing strategy and led a team of developers in its implementation (using on-site VMWare ESXi servers and Amazon AWS cloud). Visualized performance results with InfluxDB and Grafana. Authored a Capacity Planning Guide that provided recommendations for large scale deployments based on performance test results.

Designed, implemented, and led a team of devs on an automated migration strategy for a major version change.

BeauTec

Solution Developer

March 2011 - January 2013 (1 year 11 months)

Sillingy, France

Developed modular integration software based on .NET technologies (C#, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, and SQL Server).

Interfaced to business logic implemented in PL/SQL (Oracle DB).

Developed ADO.NET interfaces to 3rd party libraries (SAP, OPC, SciForma, and OSISoft Pi System) that were consumed in a modular integration solution. Developed custom integration solutions in Java and ported applications to iOS (Objective-C).

Implementation of work process improvements including continuous integration, distributed source control, and style guides.

m:pro IT Consult
Senior Software Engineer
March 2011 - January 2013 (1 year 11 months)

Wiesbaden Area, Germany

Developed modular integration software based on .NET technologies (C#, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, and SQL Server).

Interfaced to business logic implemented in PL/SQL (Oracle DB).

Developed ADO.NET interfaces to 3rd party libraries (SAP, OPC, SciForma, and OSISoft Pi System) that were consumed in a modular integration solution. Developed custom integration solutions in Java and ported applications to iOS (Objective-C).

Implementation of work process improvements including continuous integration, distributed source control, and style guides.

Hamilton Company

Senior Firmware Engineer

January 2009 - March 2011 (2 years 3 months)

Developed firmware in C++ for ARM based microprocessors with an emphasis on precision motion control and stepper motors.

Developed firmware that interfaced to memory mapped I/O devices.

Developed C# libraries for interfacing to low-level functionality using RPC calls over various transports (TCP/IP, CAN, LIN, SPI, I2C, and RS-232).

Developed embedded controller using Windows Compact Embedded including device drivers (C++ and C), API libraries (C# using manged to unmanaged interops), Board Support Package (C++ and C), applications (C#). Authored ISO 9001 documentation including requirements, design, and validation documents.

IGT

Firmware Engineer
July 2007 - December 2008 (1 year 6 months)

Developed firmware for USB controlled peripherals (C and Assembly) using motion control and PWM algorithms.

Designed and implemented a networking protocol for a multi-player "community play" game (C++).

Game development using an internally developed game engine (C++) running on top of QNX operating system.

Authored technical documentation.

Developed and maintained testing tools (C#).

ATS Automation Tooling Systems Mechanical Technician 2000 - 2003 (3 years)

Education

Oregon Institute of Technology
Bachelor of Science (x2), Computer Engineering Technology; Software
Engineering Technology · (2003 - 2007)